STELLA GORDON-ZIGEL

WEB DEVELOPER

sgordonzigel@gmail.com | stellagordonzigel.github.io | Washington, D.C. | (410) 978-6806

PROFILE

I'm a creative-minded, precise individual with a passion for collaborating with others to strategically think about real-world, web-based projects and design intuitive solutions based on current needs, trends and industry standards to create the best user experience.

SKILLS

HTML/CSS
Javascript/jQuery
Ruby on Rails
Active Record
PSQL, SQL
Git/GitHub
MERN Stack
(MongoDB,
Express.js,
React.js, Node.js)

Heroku
RESTful APIs
Responsive Design
Drupal
The Franchise
Builders
WordPress
Zoho
Basecamp
WorkZone

EDUCATION

General Assembly, Web Development Immersive

Washington, D.C. | Oct. 2017 - Jan. 2018

University of Maryland, B.A. in Communication, Rhetoric and Political Culture Track, Minor in Human Development, CIVICUS Citation College Park, MD | Aug. 2015

CEA Barcelona, Spanish Language & Culture

Barcelona, Spain | Jan. 2014 - May 2014

EXPERIENCE

WEB DEVELOPMENT IMMERSIVE STUDENT, GENERAL ASSEMBLY

October 2017 - Present

Washington, D.C.

- Built fluency in full-stack web development by completing an intensive 500-hour program focused on core languages and best practices in object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and test-driven development
- Developed a portfolio of individual and collaborative projects:
 - The One With All The Trivia tests the users' knowledge of Friends in 60 seconds. (JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS)
 - **bMORE FIT** allows users to view a library of workouts within several different categories and track the workouts they complete (Ruby on Rails, Active Record, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS)
 - **LearnNGrow** a visual learning app in the style of short quizzes intended to help young children learn in an engaging environment (React, Axios, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Node, Express, MongoDB)
 - ${\bf Pix}$ users can upload images and apply filters (React, jQuery, CSSgram, CSS)

COMMUNICATIONS COORDINATOR, SANDLER TRAINING

August 2016 - September 2017

Owings Mills, MD

- Developed field communications messaging to the ~220 person Franchise Network relative to corporate initiatives, designed in StreamSend
- Provided StreamSend technical support to internal users and 120 franchisees, including template creation, list segmenting, and best practices for effective email marketing
- Managed corporate website's (Drupal) and franchisee sitelets' (The Franchise Builders) content and layout

SITELET SUPPORT SPECIALIST, SANDLER TRAINING

February 2016 - August 2016

Owings Mills, MD

- Integral part of sitelet transition process for ~220 US and International Franchisees
- Co-created a help sitelet, providing franchisees with in-depth instructions on updating all aspects of their new sitelets

RESEARCH ASSISTANT, EARLY CHILDHOOD INTERACTION LAB

June 2014 - December 2014

College Park, MD

- Recruited 50 parent-child pairs for study
- Transcribed dialogue, actions, and gestures present in 15 minutes of parent and child play with toys and materials intended to promote understanding of fraction concepts

POLICY INTERN, PR COLLABORATIVE

September 2013 - December 2013

Washington, D.C.

• Researched clients and compiled lists of contacts specializing in subjects aligning with our clients' work, called and emailed journalists and organizations to pitch the work of our clients